A Guide to the Watkins Family Papers, ca. 1910-2000 (bulk ca. 1930-1960)
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Watkins Family Papers ca. 1910-2000 (bulk ca. 1930-1960)
The Library of Virginia
42063
1.65 cu. ft. (5 boxes)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Purchased July 2005.
Biographical Information
Dr. George W. Watkins was born in Pickens County, South Carolina, on 17 October 1898, son of James and Lattie Watkins. He died in Quinton, New Kent County, Virginia, on 26 September 1972 and was buried at Elam Baptist Church, Ruthville, Virginia. Dr. Watkins attended Virginia Union University where he received a Bachelor of Arts and an Honorary Doctor of Divinity Degree, and Hampton Institute where he received a Master of Arts Degree. He served as pastor of Second Liberty Baptist Church of Quinton and Elam Baptist Church of Ruthville, Virginia. He was also principal of New Kent Training School and the George W. Watkins Elementary and High School for over 30 years.
Watkins was married to Thelma Jones (1904-2005), daughter of Sedley Dixon Jones (b. 1877) and Mary Lou Carpenter Jones, furniture store owners in Richmond, Virginia. Thelma Jones Watkins attended Armstrong High School in Richmond and received her degree from Virginia Union University in 1926. She was a librarian and teacher at the George W. Watkins Elementary and High School, retiring in 1964.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1910-2000, (bulk ca. 1930-1960), of the Watkins and Jones families of Quinton and Richmond, Virginia. Includes certificates, clippings, correspondence, photographs, programs, receipts, and yearbooks relating mainly to George Washington Watkins (1898-1972) and his wife, Thelma Jones Watkins (1904-2005). The bulk of the collection consists of photographs of the Watkins and Jones families at social gatherings, family events, church, and school.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
Series I. Papers, ca. 1930-2000.
Series II. Photographs, ca. 1910-1994.
Contents List
- Series I: Papers, ca. 1930-2000., Extent: .25 cubic feet. (Box 1)
  This series includes advertising blotters from the Richmond Paper Company, certificates for Thelma Watkins, clippings, Christmas and birthday cards, funeral programs, and blank receipts from Sedley D. Jones furniture store in Richmond. Also included are yearbooks for the George W. Watkins School (1958, 1959, 1965) and Virginia Union University (1969).
  Arranged alphabetically by folder title.
  - Advertising blotters, nd (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Cards, ca. 1950-2000 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Certificates, 1947-1977 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Clippings, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Funeral programs, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Receipts, ca. 1930 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Yearbooks, The Lion, George W. Watkins School, 1958 (Box 1)
  - Yearbooks, The Lion, George W. Watkins School, 1959 (Box 1)
  - Yearbooks, The Lion, George W. Watkins School, 1965 (Box 1)
  - Yearbooks, Virginia Union University, 1969 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous, nd (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Series II: Photographs, 1910-1994, Extent: 1.4 cubic feet. (Box 1-5)
  This series includes photographs, ca. 1910-1994, of the Jones, Watkins, and related families of Quinton and Richmond, Virginia. Other surnames of note include: Bassett, Boykins, Bryant, Burrell, Carter, Crump, Dailey, Jefferson, Johnson, Otey, Storrs, Taylor, Washington, and Williams. Many of the photographs depict social gatherings, family, church, and school events, and provide insight into the social life of an African American family during the mid-twentieth century. Included are numerous photographs of students, as well as teachers and other administrative staff, from George W. Watkins School, often with dedications to the Watkins'. Included are photographs of Elam Baptist Church, Second Liberty Church, Virginia Union University, and George W. Watkins School. Also included are photographs of picnics, graduations, military service men, and sporting events. Of note are photographs of the Jones family as children and young women, ca. 1910-1930, and the store front of Sedley D. Jones furniture store in Richmond, Virginia. The series is grouped into individual photographs, group photographs, miscellaneous photographs, and photograph albums. For preservation reasons the photograph albums were unbound and a numbering system was created to maintain the original order. A photocopy of each album was made to create a key to the photographs and is available at the beginning of each album. Many of the photographs were identified and for those without identification, the archivist tried to provide some type of description and date range.
  - INDIVIDUALS:
  - Alberta Adkins, ca. 1970 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Rose Thompson Allen, ca. 1920 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Barcroft family, ca. 1920-1960 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Curtis J. Bassett, ca. 1960 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Inez Otey Belcher, ca. 1950 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Naomi Bobbi, ca. 1955 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Reverend Guy Boykins, ca. 1960 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Julia Banks Braxton, ca. 1950 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Criscella Brown, ca. 1980 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - John Carpenter, ca. 1910-1920 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - James M. Charity, ca. 1940 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Crump family, ca. 1920, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Charles Curl, Jr., ca. 1940 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Antoinette Dailey, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Darcie C. Dance, ca. 1930 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Elista Davis, ca. 1940 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Pearl Davis and Pharlania Davis, ca. 1930 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Todd Walter Dillard, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Charles Fletcher, ca. 1940 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Dr. Franklin, ca. 1960 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Gordon Hancock, ca. 1930-1940 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - George Jefferson, ca. 1950 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Helen and John Jefferson, ca. 1950 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Freda Johnson, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - George Johnson, ca. 1940 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Patricia Johnson, ca. 1960 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Jones family, ca. 1910-1985 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Rose Brown Lewis, ca. 1960 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Lightfoot family, ca. 1940 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Dianne Miles, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Alvara L. Mitchell, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Michele Lori-An Montague, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Gladys Morris, ca. 1940 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Lloyd Morse, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Curtis Petty, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - C. Edward Price, ca. 1940 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Roanes family, ca. 1960 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Sylvia Mitchell Scott, ca. 1910 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Storrs family, ca. 1920-1930 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Mary Taylor, ca. 1950 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Sadie Irene Turner, ca. 1940 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - George W. Watkins, ca. 1920-1940 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - George W. Watkins, ca. 1940-1970 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - George W. and Thelma Jones Watkins, ca. 1940-1970 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Thelma Jones Watkins, ca. 1920-1998 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Antoinette Dailey Williams, ca. 1940 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Eugene Williams, ca. 1980 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Richard Williams (negative), undated (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Rudolph Williams, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Alberta E. Winston, ca. 1940 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - GROUPS:
  - Identified groups, ca. 1940-1992 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    1. Children in front of school bus, ca. 1950. Includes Herman Washington, Calvin Otey, Harvey Christian, Andrew Morris, Howard Murray, Joseph Christian, John Jefferson, Irvin Johnson, and Harry Otey.
    2. Group in house, ca. 1950. Includes Lewis Johnson, Oraphine Crump, and Edna Bassett.
    3. Group in house, ca. 1950. Includes Mrs. Johnson and Mrs. Rosa Lewis.
    4. Group of women in kitchen, 1964. Includes Lavern Johnson, LaRose Abrams, Shirley Abrams, and Louise Christian.
    5. Group of men in school in suits, ca. 1960. Includes Crawford Brown, Williams, and Roses Bassett.
    6. Group from Class of 1942, Virginia Union University. Includes Oraphine Crump, Lillian Gardner, Pauline Gilmore, Bernice Meekins, Doris Patterson, Carrie Chambers, Fannie Burrell, Olivia Robinson, Christina Simon, Gladys Street, Bernice Taylor, Annie Ware, and Lueitha Lee.
  - Unidentified groups, ca. 1940-1985 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Unidentified men, ca. 1940-1950 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Unidentified women, ca. 1930-1986 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - MISCELLANEOUS:
  - Elam Baptist Church (Ruthville, Va.), ca. 1930-1950 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Fairfield and Varina Sunday School Union, ca. 1960 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - George W. Watkins School (Quinton, Va.), ca. 1940-1960 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - St. Peter's Episcopal Church (New Kent County, Va.), ca. 1950 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Second Liberty Church (New Kent County, Va.), 1969 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Third Baptist Church (Hampton, Va.), Tidewater Regional Meeting B.G.A., 1966 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Virginia Union University (Richmond, Va.), Ceramics Class Summer Seminar, ca. 1960 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - PHOTOGRAPH ALBUMS:
  - Photograph Album #1, Index Key (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Photograph Album #1 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    1. Man and woman on couch, ca. 1960-1970
    2. Same man and woman and another couple on couch, ca. 1960-1970
    3. Young man and woman outside, possibly prom, ca. 1940-1950
    4. Young man and woman outside, possibly prom, ca. 1940-1950
    5. Both young couples outside, possibly prom, ca. 1940-1950
    6. Young man and woman outside, possibly prom, ca. 1940-1950
    7. Man opening door of car, ca. 1940-1950
    8. Woman and man in front of car, 1940-1950
    9. Two men and woman outside of house, ca. 1940-1950
    10. Two men outside of house, ca. 1940-1950
    11. Man opening door of car, ca. 1940-1950
    12. Two women outside, ca. 1940-1950
    13. Marjorie Harris Carter, ca. 1950
    14. Man and woman on couch, ca. 1940-1950
    15. Longwood Gardens (Pa.), Summer 1960
    16. Two women in cap and gown, ca. 1950
    17. Second Liberty Baptist Church Men's Club, after working on church grounds, 1959
    18. Thelma and Hugo Carl, ca. 1950-1960
    19. Second Liberty Baptist Church Men's Club, after working on church grounds, 1959
    20. Man on couch, ca. 1940-1950
    21. Women's Missionary Sisters of Second Liberty Baptist Church, 1959
    22. Man in laboratory, ca. 1950-1960
    23. George Jefferson in military uniform, ca. 1950
    24. Franklin Christian (Lanexa, Va), 1951
    25. Nannie and Matthew Burell, ca. 1950
    26. George W. Washington School boys raking in a garden, ca. 1950
    27. Man and woman in house, ca. 1950
    28. Mamie Frances S. Bell and Kathleen Boykins visiting the George W. Watkins School, 1968
    29. Alton Taylor, ca. 1950
    30. Anna Cora Pemberton, Luther Washington, and Luther W. Wilkins, ca. 1950
    31. Josephine, unidentified woman, and two men, at Christmas, ca. 1940-1950
    32. The W.A. Green family, ca. 1950-1960
    33. Three men in front of church, ca. 1940-1950
    34. Purcell Bell, Mamie Starrs Bell, Blanche Thompson Mitchell, Kathleen Ryland Boykins, and Thelma Jones Watkins, ca. 1970
    35. Mamie Frances S. Bell and Kathleen Boykins visiting the George W. Watkins School, Quinton, 1968
    36. Lottie Harris and Bertha Watkins, ca. 1950
    37. Family group photograph outside, ca. 1950
    38. Floyd Patterson Jr. school photograph, ca. 1960-1970
    39. Joseph Johnson school photograph (age 12), 1977
    40. Sophia Logan Terry and class, ca. 1960
    41. LaVerne Johnson, ca. 1950-1960
    41a. Jerome, 1951
    42. Family group inside house, ca. 1950-1960
    43. Benny Ira Crump Jr. school photograph, ca. 1960
    44. Bennie Ira Crump Jr. school photograph, 1964
    45. Thelma Janice Watkins school photograph, ca. 1960
    46. Thelma Janice Watkins school photograph (age 12), 1964
    47. Jean Macon school photograph, ca. 1960
    48. Jerome Lee Johnson school photograph (age 15, 10th grade), February 1960
    49. Marjorie Carter, ca. 1950-1960
    50. Cynthia Lewis school photograph, ca. 1960
    51. Sylvia Lewis school photograph (age 14, 8th grade), February 1964
  - Photograph Album #2, Index Key (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Photograph Album #2 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    1. George W. Watkins portrait photograph, ca. 1960s
    2. Group in front of school, ca. 1950-1960
    3. Barbara Jean Rose school photograph (age 7), ca. 1960
    4. Northumberland County first class, ca. 1940-1950
    5. Children in front of school bus, ca. 1940-1950
    6. Lisa W. school photograph (age 14), 1977
    7. Three women on couch, ca. 1950
    8. Mr. and Mrs. Strother and daughter, 1933
    9. Unidentified school photograph, ca. 1960
    10. George W. Watkins and Thelma Watkins, Anniversary banquet, ca. 1960
    11. Thelma Dixon Carl, Charles Hugo Carl, and Thelma J. Watkins, ca. 1940-1950
    12. Violet, ca. 1970-1980
    13. Winfree Carter and Rose Rowe, ca. 1940
    14. Thelma Jones Watkins, ca. 1950-1960
    15. Two women and one man in front of car, ca. 1950-1960
    16. Shelly Montague school photograph (age 9 1/2, mother Caroline Jones Montague, grandparents Lucille and Otis), 1980
    17. Rhonda Delina school photograph (age 8), ca. 1970-1980
    18. Duncan Williams school photograph, ca. 1970-1980
    19. Letitia Williams school photograph (age 12), 1977
    20. Group of young men crossing guards in front of school, ca. 1950-1960
    21. Clement Watkins as a child with grandfather's lunch pail, ca. 1920
    22. Thelma Watkins and Jettie Anders, 1957
    23. Group of women in front of school, ca. 1940-1950
    24. Group of three men and two women on vacation, ca. 1950
    25. Group photograph of men, women, and children (blurry), ca. 1950
    26. Young lady in saddle shoes sitting on porch, ca. 1950
    27. Thelma Winston and another young lady, ca. 1930s
    28. Christmas photograph card of Mr. and Mrs. George W. Watkins, ca. 1970
    29. Clipping and photograph of Miss Virginia Union, Yvonne A. Thompson (Quinton, Va.), 1964-1965
    30. Rupert Picott and [unidentified] Nixon, ca. 1970
    31. Family, mother, father, and two children, in front of a Model T Ford, ca. 1920
    32. Two women sitting on couch, ca. 1960
    33. Christmas photograph card of the Hendersons (Tom, Kat, and T-Z), Virginia Union University, ca. 1960-1970
    34. Sedley D. Jones, Jr. (Bronx, NY), 1972
    35. Second Liberty Church Annex, 1969
    36. Sedley Dixon Jones (1920-1983), photograph and obituary, 1983
    37. Man and child in yard in front of well, ca. 1940-1950
    38. Lillian Jones Dailey and Gay Jones in front of fence, ca. 1920-1930
    39. Young man standing on boulders, ca. 1940-1950
    40. Choir of young men and women, ca. 1960
    41. Graduation cap and gown photograph of Antoinette Dailey Williams, ca. 1960
    42. Estelle Watkins and sister [George Washington's aunt-in-law], ca. 1930
    43. Kerry Williams (age 8), 1970
    44. Lillian Jones, Gay Jones, and another woman on front; on back photograph of man and woman, ca. 1930-1940
    45. Elder woman sitting in chair, ca. 1950
    46. Group of seven young women in uniform: 1st girl unidentified, 2. Thelma Carter, 3. Maude Lawrence, 4. Ida Robinson, 5. Julia Crump Taylor, 6. Jean Street, 7. Willie Ann Bailey, ca. 1940-1950
  - Photograph Album #3, Index key (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Photograph Album #3, Photos 1-30 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    1. Antoinette (age 7), Marietta (age 9), Lillian (age 11), and Edward Williams (age 13), ca. 1940-1950
    2. George W. Watkins (1898-1972), ca. 1970
    3. George W. Watkins on riding mower in yard, ca. 1970
    4. Lillian Dailey, ca. 1970
    5. George W. Watkins and Thelma Jones Watkins, ca. 1960
    6. Lillian Dailey Williams and family, ca. 1950-1960 (same as #23)
    7. George Washington and Thelma Watkins (Quinton, Va.), 28 July 1940
    8. Mimi Ruth Elrod school photograph, ca. 1970
    9. Kerry Williams school photograph, 1979
    10. Unidentified school photograph, ca. 1970
    11. Kanika Nicholson (age 2 1/2; daughter of Karen Williams), November 1982
    12. Clipping of school photographs of Jean Bolden and Earl Roberts, ca. 1970
    13. Tia Petty school photograph (age 12, daughter of Curtis and Gladys Dailey Petty), 1982
    14. Jacquelin, Michael, and Quincy Bryant family photograph (mother Marietta Dailey Bryant), ca. 1980
    15. Quincy Bryant school photograph, 1981
    16. Lisa W. school photograph (5th grade), ca. 1980
    17. Francis, John Thomas, and George Washington Watkins, 1968
    18. Tia Petty school photograph (5th grade, daughter of Curtis and Gladys Dailey Petty), 1979
    19. Jamal A. Hawkins (born 24 December 1976, mother Dixon Hawkins), June 1976
    20. Lisa Williams school photograph (age 7, parents Rudolph and Antoinette Dailey Williams), May 1970
    21 Family picnic, ca. 1970
    22. Thelma J. Watkins, ca. 1970
    23. Lillian Dailey Williams and family, ca. 1950-1960 (same as #6)
    24. Elam Baptist Church, ca. 1960-1970
    25. Bernie and Bob Watkins, ca. 1960-1970
    26. Christmas greeting card
    27. Postcard photograph of three men, ca. 1920-1930
    28. Man standing outside, ca. 1920-1930
    29. Seasons greetings photograph card of Mr. and Mrs. John Jefferson and boys, ca. 1970
    30. Pearl Olivia Harwell (born 10 September 1943), 1943
  - Photograph Album #3, Photos 31-54 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    31. Anniversary of George and Thelma Watkins, cutting cake, ca. 1960-1970
    32. Anniversary of George and Thelma Watkins, cutting cake, ca. 1960-1970
    33. Rosa Strother, 1968
    34. Robert Watkins (Detroit, Michigan), ca. 1970
    35. Children of Lillian and Ed Williams (Rodney, Karen, and Edward Williams), ca. 1950-1960
    36. Estelle Watkins, ca. 1950-1960
    37. Second Liberty Church picnic group, ca. 1960-1970
    38. Rudolph Williams family (Kirk, Curry, Lisa, Letitia, Antoinette (mother), and family dog), ca. 1960-1970
    39. Four ladies in church pews, ca. 1960-1970
    40. Second Liberty Church, ca. 1960-1970
    41. Group outside church: Louise Christian, Matthew Burrell, Marian Williams, Dally Christian, Nannie Burrell, Dannie Fox, and George W. Watkins, ca. 1950-1960
    42. Second Liberty Church Senior choir, ca. 1950-1960
    43. Miss Almeria Edmunds after lecture on Japan at Elam Baptist, 5 March 1961
    44. Ministers Alliance (New Kent County, Va.), including Reverend Braxton, Reverend Boykins, Reverend Charity, and Reverend Crump, ca. 1960
    45. Second Liberty Church Junior choir, ca. 1950-1960
    46. Group photograph of women and children in park, ca. 1950-1960
    47. Repast after rehearsal Second Liberty Junior Choir. Includes Janet Christian, June Williams, Jean Bolling, Marilyn Christian, Romaine Dixon, and Sylvia Lewis, ca. 1965
    48. Second Liberty Church Youth Activity at home of Reverend and Mrs. Watkins. Includes Marilyn Christina, Iris Crump, Jean Bolling, Dulcinia Williams, Romain Dixon, [unidentified] Bassett, Oraphine Crump, Bennie Crump, Kenneth Brown, Lewis Johnson, and Sylvia Lewis, ca. 1965
    49. Mrs. Murray's class, ca. 1950-1960
    50. Vernice Jones (8th grade), 5 November 1955
    51. Grace's boy, Joldie school photograph, 1950-1951
    52. Stanley Thompson (Tunstal, Va.), 1951
    53. Ruby Jefferson (George W. Watkins School), 8 October 1951
    54. Group photograph, ca. 1950
  - Photograph Album #4 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    1. George W. Watkins School after luncheon given by Principal Watkins. Includes Mrs. Mary Watkins, Miss Annie Franklin, Thelma Watkins, Mrs. Cordelia Banks, and Mr. S.A. Crutchfield, ca. 1950-1960
    2. Mr. Ned Thornton, shop teacher; Mrs. Mary Green, home economics; Mr. Dillard Sciences, second principal, ca. 1950-1960
    3. George W. Watkins and Edward Whitehead (Little Elam Church, Charles City, Va.), ca. 1950-1960
    4. Mrs. Edythe Harris presenting gift on behalf of faculty of George W. Watkins School on occasion of Mr. Thornton's resignation, ca. 1950-1960
    5. Reverend and family, also Thelma Watkins and Mary Hawkins, ca. 1950-1960
    6. Reverend and family, also Thelma Watkins and Mary Hawkins, ca. 1950-1960
    7. Group of three unidentified adults and children, ca. 1950-1960
    8. Mrs. Pauline Craddock, Supervisor, George W. Watkins School, ca. 1950-1960
  - Photograph Album #5 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    1. Little Elam Church, (Charles City, Va.), ca. 1950-1960
    2. Papa Lawrence, Mama Ernestine, Grandma Rosa, Boss Karen, and Ma Thelma, ca. 1960
    3. Ora and friend, ca. 1960
    4. "Wintertime is really here and Mrs. Murray is enjoying it." Photograph of snow covered car and house, ca. 1950
    5. Volunteer work force at Second Liberty Baptist Church, 1958
    6. Ora and friends, ca. 1960
    7. Mrs. Murray in front of snow covered car and house, ca. 1950
    8. Karen Johnson sitting at piano, ca. 1950-1960
    9. Lawrence, Ernestine, Rosa, T.J., and Karen, ca. 1950-1960
  - Photograph Album #6 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    Group of photographs of family members on a couch and includes photographs of a bride in her wedding gown. Few that are identified are Elaine and Bill Brown and Ora Williams. Last photograph is of a classroom, ca. 1950-1960.
  - Photograph Album #7, Index key (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Photograph Album #7, Photos 1-33 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    1. George W. Watkins, ca. 1960
    2. Criscella Brown (daughter of James Brown, Charles City, Va.), 1970
    3. Lilly Wilson and Stan Elliot, 1969
    4. Thelma Watkins and Pauline Craddock, ca. 1960
    5. Mrs. Helen Dixon, ca. 1960
    6. Mrs. Helen Dixon, ca. 1960
    7. Seasons greeting photograph card of Mary Ellen Steward to Mr. and Mrs. Alphonso Mann, ca. 1960
    8. Gladys Street, 14 December 1944
    9. Ruth and Ruby Jefferson, ca. 1940
    10. Seasons greeting photograph card from The J.A. Bowler family, 1950
    10a. Sylvester Johnson, ca. 1960
    10b. Barbara Johnson (daughter of Maria and James Johnson, Richmond, Va.), ca. 1960
    11. Bobby Watkins (age 12, 5th grade), 10 June 1964
    12. Bertha Watkins (age 9), 23 May 1950
    13. Ora Williams and Margaret Randolph, ca. 1950
    14. Maria Davis (Johnson), ca. 1950
    15. Joyce Braxton, George W. Watkins School, 1964
    16. Joyce Braxton, George W. Watkins School, 1964
    17. Susie Haywood (cousin of Watkins, South Carolina), ca. 1970
    18. Mabel Patterson birthday party. Includes Bessie Miller, Thelma Watkins, and Louise Christian, 15 June 1990
    19. Three men in military uniform, ca. 1940-1950
    20. Spurgeon Taylor, ca. 1970
    21. George W. Watkins, ca. 1960
    22. Seasons greeting photograph card of Edwin and Rosa (Buffalo, NY), 1951
    23. Ernest Watkins, ca. 1950
    24. John Thomas Watkins, ca. 1970
    25. Helen Brown, Althea Christian, and Lillian Mae Johnson, ca. 1950
    26. Landonna Jefferson (New Kent, Va.), ca. 1960
    27. Thelma and Gay, ca. 1940-1950
    28. William Brown in uniform (Quinton, Va.), ca. 1950
    29. Larry Christian in uniform, August 1978
    30. George Otey, George W. Watkins School, 1969
    31. Frank Christian, Jr. school photograph, 1976
    32. Mary F. Hill school photograph, 6 June 1950
    33. Birthday greetings to Mrs. Watkins on 95th Birthday, from the Bible Study Group, Edmund Whitehead Chairman, 25 May 1999
  - Photograph Album #7, Photos 34-74 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    34. Mary L. Hawkins, ca. 1950
    35. Mary L. Hawkins, ca. 1960
    36. Principal Watkins School, Todd Dillan, ca. 1960
    37. Ned Thornton and wife, ca. 1950
    38. Mr. and Mrs. John Robinson 50th Anniversary (New Kent, Va.), ca. 1960
    39. Mrs. Louisa Christian, Mrs. Sophia Logan Terry (Home Ec. Teacher), and Mrs. Mary Johnson, ca. 1950
    40. Julie Lewis, Marie Thompson, and Gordon Thompson, ca. 1970
    41. Elnora Bassett, William Brown, and Romaine Dixon, ca. 1940
    42. Joyce Braxton, Stanley Tyler, and Miss Porter, ca. 1960
    43. Student Council Leaders. Local state and visitors from other schools: Miss Mary Hawkins, George W. Watkins School, Yvonne Thompson, and Jerome Johnson, 24 March 1961